{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"Neurotoxins","incorrectAnswers":["Neurovenoms","Endotoxins","Endovenoms"],"question":"What is the name given to a poison that acts on the nervous system?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Metallica","incorrectAnswers":["Alice Cooper","The Pussycat Dolls","Three 6 Mafia"],"question":"Which American heavy metal band released the studio album 'Death Magnetic'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"vibrations and oscillations in the Sun","incorrectAnswers":["origin of life","earthquakes","alternative method of massage, manipulative therapy|therapy or pressure on certain points of the sole of the feet as a means of relieving nervous tension"],"question":"What is Helioseismology the study of?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"BMW","incorrectAnswers":["Harley Davidson","Mercedez-Benz","Porsche"],"question":"Which motoring brand is associated with the marketing slogan 'The Ultimate Driving Machine'?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Ring of Fire","incorrectAnswers":["MacArthur Park","Can't Get Used to Losing You","Landslide"],"question":"Which song, originally recorded by Johnny Cash, was later covered by Wall of Voodoo?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Gustave Flaubert","incorrectAnswers":["Anatole France","Guy de Maupassant","Charles Perrault"],"question":"Which author wrote 'Bouvard et Pécuchet'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Pennsylvania","incorrectAnswers":["Ohio","Indiana","Maryland"],"question":"Which U.S. state has communities called Lititz, Ephrata, and Strasburg in its Amish Country?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Saudi Arabia","incorrectAnswers":["Guinea-Bissau","Samoa","Slovakia"],"question":"Which region of the world uses '.sa' at the end of its web addresses?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Ukraine","incorrectAnswers":["Tajikistan","Poland","Lithuania"],"question":"Kyiv is the capital city of which country?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"The FSB","incorrectAnswers":["The EU","The WHO","Interpol"],"question":"What organisation is based in the  Lubjlyanka building?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"Mythical animals","incorrectAnswers":["Blackberries","Allergies","Flags"],"question":"What is Cryptozoology the study of?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Arizona/Nevada","incorrectAnswers":["California/Nevada","Utah/Colorado","Utah/Nevada"],"question":"On which state border is the Hoover Dam? ","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Orson Welles","incorrectAnswers":["Louis Figaro","Jack Thomas","Eugene Lamonde"],"question":"Whose radio production of War Of The World's caused panic in America in 1938?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Charles Darwin","incorrectAnswers":["Percy Bysshe Shelley","H. Rider Haggard","Robert Louis Stevenson"],"question":"Which author wrote 'The Descent of Man And Selection in Relation to Sex'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Foreshortening","incorrectAnswers":["Isometric Projection","Topomorphism","Skewed Perspective"],"question":"Which art technique can be described as \"Reducing or distorting in order to represent three-dimensional space as perceived by the eye\"?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"Bacchus","incorrectAnswers":["Apollo","Zeus","Hermes"],"question":"Which wine god's orgiastic worship was suppressed by the Roman Senate in the 180s BC?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"El Dorado","incorrectAnswers":["Atlantis","Shangri-La","Camelot"],"question":"What fabled city was German adventurer Philipp Von Hutten searching for when he explored South America in the 1540s?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Shinto","incorrectAnswers":["Buddhism","Taoism","Hinduism"],"question":"What is the name of the Japanese religion that has many sects including Fukko and Watarai?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"Animal behaviour","incorrectAnswers":["The Earth's atmosphere","Glaciers","Friction and lubrication"],"question":"What is Ethology the study of?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"1997","incorrectAnswers":["1989","1993","2001"],"question":"In which year was Good Will Hunting released?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"James Whistler","incorrectAnswers":["Andy Warhol","Grant Wood","Eddie Harold"],"question":"Which american artist is known for a portrait of his mother?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"The Fresh Prince of Bel-Air","incorrectAnswers":["Seinfeld","Friends","Home Improvement"],"question":"What was the name of the popular '90s sitcom starring Will Smith?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Arthur Conan Doyle","incorrectAnswers":["Agatha Christie","Oscar Wilde","George Orwell"],"question":"Which author wrote 'The Adventures of Sherlock Holmes'?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"general_knowledge","correctAnswer":"The Hay","incorrectAnswers":["The Manger","A Donkey","The Stars"],"question":"In the Christmas carol 'Away in a Manger', what was the little Lord Jesus asleep on?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"A leader tries to expand his empire while a poor barber tries to avoid persecution.","incorrectAnswers":["Two men join in an uneasy alliance against a third to find gold buried in a remote cemetery.","A weatherman finds himself trapped in a small town as he lives the same day over and over again.","A surgeon rescues a disfigured man who is mistreated while scraping a living as a side-show freak."],"question":"What is the plot of the movie The Great Dictator?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"The Rolling Stones","incorrectAnswers":["Black","Sticky Fingers","Brown Sugar"],"question":"What was the title of the first album released by The Rolling Stones?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"1989","incorrectAnswers":["1984","1994","1999"],"question":"When did the scientist Tim Berners-Lee invent the World Wide Web?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"The Moscow Treaty","incorrectAnswers":["The Berlin Treaty","The Warsaw Treaty","The Yalta Treaty"],"question":"1970 Saw Which Treaty Between USSR & West Germany","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"Appendix","incorrectAnswers":["Bowel","Spleen","Pancreas"],"question":"Which fingerlike projection is attached to the large intestine?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"\"Hooked on a Feeling\" by B.J. Thomas","incorrectAnswers":["\"Immigrant Song\" by Led Zeppelin","\"What I Got\" by Sublime","\"American Pie\" by Don McLean"],"question":"Which song begins with the lyrics: \"Ooga-chaka, Ooga-ooga / Ooga-chaka, Ooga-ooga...\"?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"France","incorrectAnswers":["Austria","Benin","North Africa"],"question":"Crêpes are most associated with which part of the world?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Blue","incorrectAnswers":["Green","Gold","Black"],"question":"Which of these colors would you find on the flag of United Kingdom?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Tommy Lee","incorrectAnswers":["Nikki Sixx","Vince Neil","Mick Mars"],"question":"Who was Pamela Anderson married to before her brief marriage to Kid Rock?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"The Beach Boys","incorrectAnswers":["Swans","Three 6 Mafia","The Velvet Underground"],"question":"Which American rock band released the song 'God Only Knows'?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Snowflake","incorrectAnswers":["Buttercup","Pumpkin","Cupcake"],"question":"What slang term refers to a very sensitive person who is easily offended?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"Elizabeth I","incorrectAnswers":["James III","Victoria","Henry VIII"],"question":"Who ruled England at the time of Shakespeare?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Green","incorrectAnswers":["Nine","Red","Six"],"question":"In French, what is the meaning of the word 'vert'?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"dietetics","incorrectAnswers":["intonation in speech","in ethics, duty","fossils of ancient life"],"question":"What is Sitiology the study of?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"Apple ","incorrectAnswers":["Grape","Banana","Cherry"],"question":"Blanche Ames, Lord Lambourne and Willis Williams are all varieties of _________","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Monrovia","incorrectAnswers":["Brazzaville","Ulaanbaatar","Nur-Sultan"],"question":"What is the capital city of Liberia?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Paul Cézanne","incorrectAnswers":["Henri Rousseau","‎‎Johannes Vermeer","Mark Rothko"],"question":"Which artist painted \"The Bathers\"","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Jonathan Swift","incorrectAnswers":["William Godwin","Voltaire","Henry Fielding"],"question":"Who wrote \"Gullivers Travels\"?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"12 Angry Men","incorrectAnswers":["American History X","All About Eve","Rear Window"],"question":"Name the movie that matches the following plot summary: 'The jury in a murder trial is frustrated by a member whose caution forces them to consider the evidence.'","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"\"Life is a banquet, and most poor suckers are starving to death!\"","incorrectAnswers":["\"That is so fetch.\"","\"I am big! It's the pictures that got small.\"","\"Mother of mercy, is this the end of Rico?\""],"question":"Which of these quotes is from the film 'Auntie Mame'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Penélope Cruz","incorrectAnswers":["Amy Adams","Uma Thurman","Cameron Diaz"],"question":"Which actress has played roles in films including Pirates of the Caribbean: On Stranger Tides and Volver?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"sport_and_leisure","correctAnswer":"Cleveland Browns","incorrectAnswers":["Cleveland Whitesox","Cleveland SC","Cleveland A's"],"question":"Which of these is an American Football team based in Cleveland?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"Troy","incorrectAnswers":["Athens","Rome","Jerusalem"],"question":"What ancient city is also known as Ilium?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Sri Lanka","incorrectAnswers":["Madagascar","Belize","Fiji"],"question":"Which island nation has been called the 'teardrop of India' due to its location and shape?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Leonardo DiCaprio","incorrectAnswers":["Ralph Fiennes","Brian Cox","Kiefer Sutherland"],"question":"Which actor has featured in films including Titanic and Inception?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"The United States","incorrectAnswers":["Korea","China","Germany"],"question":"Where were fortune cookies invented?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"Mary I","incorrectAnswers":["Mary II","Maria I","Marie Antoinette"],"question":"Which Queen of England was known as Bloody Mary?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"Flea","incorrectAnswers":["Tick","Rat","Dust Mite"],"question":"What type of animal is pulex irritants?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"1958","incorrectAnswers":["1934","1942","1971"],"question":"When was the pacemaker invented?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"sport_and_leisure","correctAnswer":"The Green Bay Packers","incorrectAnswers":["The Dallas Cowboys","The Pittsburgh Steelers","The New England Patriots"],"question":"Which NFL team, known for its fans' distinctive cheese wedge hats, is also nicknamed \"Cheeseheads\"?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"Linguine","incorrectAnswers":["Orecchiette","Ditalini","Gemelli"],"question":"Which pasta's name means 'Little tongues'?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Africa","incorrectAnswers":["Asia","North America","South America"],"question":"Which is the Earth's second largest continent?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Rocky","incorrectAnswers":["Amélie","The Deer Hunter","Schindler's List"],"question":"Name the movie that matches the following plot summary: 'A small-time boxer gets a chance to fight the world heavyweight champion.'","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Green Book","incorrectAnswers":["Platoon","V for Vendetta","The Dark Knight"],"question":"Name the movie that matches the following plot summary: 'A working-class bouncer becomes the driver of an African-American classical pianist.'","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"The Pyrenees","incorrectAnswers":["The Alps","The Urals","The Pennines"],"question":"What is the name of the mountain chain separating Spain from France?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"John le Carré","incorrectAnswers":["Agatha Christie","Georges Simenon","Charles Dickens"],"question":"Which author wrote 'The Constant Gardener'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Botswana","incorrectAnswers":["Estonia","Saudi Arabia","Micronesia"],"question":"Gaborone is the capital city of which country?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"Tubular pasta","incorrectAnswers":["Soup pasta","Shaped pasta","Ribbon pasta"],"question":"What type of pasta is gomiti?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"sport_and_leisure","correctAnswer":"Super heavyweight","incorrectAnswers":["Flyweight","Heavyweight","Maxweight"],"question":"What is the heaviest class of weight-lifting?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"Egypt","incorrectAnswers":["Cambodia","Turkey","Benin"],"question":"Where in the world would you most expect to be served Kushari?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"A cyborg must protect a ten-year-old boy from a more powerful cyborg.","incorrectAnswers":["A criminal pleads insanity and is admitted to a mental institution.","An NYPD officer tries to save his wife taken hostage by terrorists during a Christmas party.","A car salesman's inept crime falls apart due to his and his henchmen's bungling."],"question":"What is the plot of the movie Terminator 2: Judgment Day?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"sport_and_leisure","correctAnswer":"Tennis","incorrectAnswers":["Snooker","Hockey","Cycling"],"question":"With which sport is John McEnroe associated?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"Pigs ","incorrectAnswers":["Sheep","Cows","Cats"],"question":"Which animal is used to sniff out truffles?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"\"Love means never having to say you're sorry.\"","incorrectAnswers":["\"Greed, for lack of a better word, is good.\"","\"May the Force be with you.\"","\"This is the day you will always remember as the day you almost caught Captain Jack Sparrow!\""],"question":"Which of these quotes is from the film 'Love Story'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Right Said Fred","incorrectAnswers":["Vanilla Ice","Musical Youth","Rob Base & DJ E-Z Rock"],"question":"Who had a hit in 1991 with I'm Too Sexy?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"Onion","incorrectAnswers":["Pepper","Tomato","Garlic"],"question":"What do you add to a martini to make it a Gibson?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Pride and Prejudice","incorrectAnswers":["The Fault in Our Stars","Ship of Fools","War and Peace"],"question":"In which book does 'George Wickham' appear?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"Flail","incorrectAnswers":["Spear","Axe","Sword"],"question":"Which of these was not a type of Viking weapon?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"Spanish Flu","incorrectAnswers":["Swine Flu","SARS","Coronavirus"],"question":"What was the name of the pandemic which killed over 1% of the world's population in 1918?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Exchange Rate","incorrectAnswers":["GDP","Inflation Rate","Currency Ratio"],"question":"What is the term for the value of one currency in relation to another currency?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"The Dead Sea Scrolls","incorrectAnswers":["The Rosetta Stone","The Nag Hammadi Library","The Gospel of Judas"],"question":"Which ancient artifact was discovered in 1947 in caves in the Qumran region of the West Bank?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Jack","incorrectAnswers":["Ensign","Pennant","Burgee"],"question":"What is the name of the flag flown on a short pole at the bow of a ship?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Sense and Sensibility","incorrectAnswers":["Pride and Prejudice","Emma","Mansfield Park"],"question":"Which novel by Jane Austen ends with sisters Marianne & Elinor Dashwood getting married?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Triton","incorrectAnswers":["Hercules","Jason","Perseus"],"question":"Who is the son of Poseidon in Greek mythology and the undersea king in a Disney movie?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"1921","incorrectAnswers":["1940","1951","1968"],"question":"In which year was the vaccine for tuberculosis created?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Karl Marx","incorrectAnswers":["Ludwig Wittgenstein","Socrates","Friedrich Nietzsche"],"question":"Which philosopher famously said 'Religion is the sign of the oppressed ... it is the opium of the people'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"Shaped pasta","incorrectAnswers":["Strand pasta","Tubular pasta","Ribbon pasta"],"question":"What type of pasta is campanelle?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Drie","incorrectAnswers":["Trois","Tres","Zeven"],"question":"In Dutch, what is the word for for 'three'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"George S. Patton","incorrectAnswers":["David Dixon Porter","George Elliot","Philip Sheridan"],"question":"Which of these people was a United States Army general during World War II?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Cratchett","incorrectAnswers":["Poorboy","Thompson","Squalor"],"question":"In 'A Christmas Carol'', what is Tiny Tim's surname","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"Port ","incorrectAnswers":["Vodka","Brandy","Amaretto"],"question":"Which drink comes in Ruby and Tawny varieties?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Seize the day","incorrectAnswers":["The time are changing, and we change in them","The act done by me against my will is not my act","A beard doesn't make one a philosopher"],"question":"How does that Latin phrase 'Carpe diem' translate into English?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"general_knowledge","correctAnswer":"The sh in 'shop'","incorrectAnswers":["The n in 'no'","The k in 'sock'","The j in 'juice'"],"question":"In phonetics, which of these is an example of a fricative sound?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"general_knowledge","correctAnswer":"Bravo","incorrectAnswers":["Boot","Ball","Baby"],"question":"What word is used in the NATO Phonetic Alphabet for the letter B?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"A pack","incorrectAnswers":["A shrewdness","A brood","A rag"],"question":"What is the word for a group of hounds?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"general_knowledge","correctAnswer":"December 6th","incorrectAnswers":["December 18th","December 25th","December 26th"],"question":"When is the Feast of St. Nicholas?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Hawaii","incorrectAnswers":["California","Alaska","Washington"],"question":"Which U.S. state has a Volcanoes National Park that includes the summit of a 13,677-foot high volcano?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Sean Connery","incorrectAnswers":["Daniel Craig","Roger Moore","Timothy Dalton"],"question":"Who played the role of James Bond in From Russia With Love?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"Y2K","incorrectAnswers":["Bug2000","Trojan Horse","The Millennial Worm"],"question":"What was the nickname given to the possible computer bug that caused worldwide concern leading up to the year 2000?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Trois","incorrectAnswers":["Tre","Drie","Noir"],"question":"In French, what is the word for for 'three'?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Sean Connery","incorrectAnswers":["Roger Moore","Timothy Dalton","Pierce Brosnan"],"question":"Which James Bond actor played the role in Dr. No and Diamonds Are Forever?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Bryan Singer","incorrectAnswers":["Steven Spielberg","Woody Allen","Martin Scorsese"],"question":"Which director directed X-Men?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"The Batman","incorrectAnswers":["Rocky","Die Hard","The Good, the Bad and the Ugly"],"question":"Name the movie that matches the following plot summary: 'When a serial killer murders key political figures, a vigilante is forced to intervene.'","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Spinning wheels","incorrectAnswers":["Candles","Pillows","Dolls"],"question":"What household objects did Sleeping Beauty's parents try to have burned?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"sport_and_leisure","correctAnswer":"Chicago Cubs","incorrectAnswers":["Chicago Capitals","Chicago Giants","Chicago Spurs"],"question":"Which of these is a baseball team based in Chicago?","difficulty":"hard"},